{
  "StartingSceneState": 0,
  "SceneStates": [
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 0,
      "Prompt": "You are standing in a guard tower within the kingdom of Denmark.  It is night time and freezing cold outside.  You are earning less than minimum wage for the job of guarding the castle.",
      "Choices": [
        "Complain to HR about your working conditions.",
        "Grin and bear.",
        "Yell \"I don't get paid enough for this.\" and clock out for the night."
      ],
      "Responses": [
        "You go to the castle's human resources after your shift is over and complain about the cold weather and darkness.  In response to your complaint, the human resources lady pulls out a sword and stabs you.  You are now dead.",
        "Choosing to grin and bear it like the man you are, you stand guard at the tower for another 2 hours.",
        "Your rage-quit is heard by other employees in the tower who subsequently alert HR.  You are fired and banished to the dungeon for gross neglegance.  You are now a slave and get paid absolutely nothing just to trim weeds all day.  Are you happy now?"
      ],
      "CorrectCHoice": 1
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 0,
      "Prompt": "Eventually, another guard arrives at your tower.  It is now time for the two of you to switch places.  Before you clock out, your very concerned and stressed out coworker asks you \"Have you seen the ghost?\"  About to leave, you answer:",
      "Choices": [
        "\"What ghost?\"",
        "\"I've seen nothing but darkness and heard nothing but wind.\"",
        "\"Nothing but that goblin that keeps appearing out of nowhere and farting in my face.  Yuck.\""
      ],
      "Responses": [
        "Confused and tired, you ask your co-worker what he's talking about.",
        "You tell your co-worker that you've seen nothing all night.  However, just as you say that, a ghost appears between the two of you.  Your co-worker exclaims \"That's the ghost!\" but it catches you off guard and you fall out of the tower to your death.  Boo!",
        "Your co-worker looks at you as if you're insane or on some sort of illegal hallucinogenic drug.  As you try to compute what's so wrong with what you said, you pass out.  In hindsight, those goblin farts MAY have been toxic."
      ],
      "CorrectChoice": 0
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 0,
      "Prompt": "\"I'm positive that, during my last shift, I saw the ghost of Lord Hamlet's late father.\" your co-worker elaborates.  As you try to recollect any sightings, that very ghost appears.  What do you do?",
      "Choices": [
        "Defend the tower.  Swing your blade at the ghost.",
        "Run for your life."
      ],
      "CorrectChoice": 0,
      "Responses": [
        "It's a ghost...the blade goes right through the ghost's body as if the ghost wasn't even there.",
        "Panicking, the two of you quickly book it down the winding stairs toward the tower's exit.  The ghost yells something unintelligible which startles you even more, and the two of you subsequently fall down 4 flights of stairs.  At least you two won the Darwin awards and spent your last moments together!"
      ]
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 0,
      "Prompt": "Realizing how dumb of an idea that was, but not ready to give up just yet, you try something else.",
      "Choices": [
        "Ask the ghost what it wants.",
      ],
      "CorrectChoice": 0,
      "Responses": [
        "The ghost stares at you with a blank expression on it's face.  It heard you loud and clear, but has no idea what in God's name you just said."
      ]
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 1,
      "Prompt": "The ghost disappears.  You two decide to stand on guard together but the ghost never shows it's face again.  Afterwards, you decide to seek the assistance of Horatio, a highly-educated \"ghost-whisperer\" of sorts, who can speak fluent Latin.",
      "Choices": [
        "Explain the ghost to Horatio.",
        "Try to talk to Horatio in Latin",
        "Ask Horatio what the meaning of life, the universe, and everything is."
      ],
      "CorrectChoice": 0,
      "Responses": [
        "\"Uhhh, I think you meant to say apparition.  That'd be the technical term for it.\" Horatio smugly replies.",
        "Horatio is bewildered.  You repeat yourself and he thinks to himself \"I don't have time for this...\" and walks away.",
        "\"42,\" Horatio replies, as a developer console for the simulation of life pops up and God types \"reboot\" and hits Enter.  Peasants like you aren't allowed to know the truth."
      ],
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 0,
      "Prompt": "Horatio's comment is factually correct, but now you're annoyed. What do you do?",
      "Choices": [
        "Yell \"NERD!\" and throw an egg at Horatio.",
        "Walk away.",
        "\"Okay. Well, I didn't know that.\"",
        "\"What the hell is an apparition?\""
      ],
      "Responses": [
        "What? Are you a 5-year-old? That's a little bit immature.  Besides, there are no eggs around to throw at Horatio.",
        "You can't walk away. You need Horatio's help to communicate with the ghost.",
        "Horatio looks at you wondering how you even passed Kindergarten not knowing that but then immediately remembers that Kindergarten doesn't even exist in the middle-ages in Denmark, and with a straight face, says \"Fair enough.\"",
        "Horatio pulls out a dictionary, flips to the definition of \"Apparition,\", and reads it to you.\r\n\r\n\"Apparition: a ghost or ghostlike image of a person.\""
      ],
      "CorrectChoice": 2,
      "LoopBack": true
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 0,
      "Prompt": "Horatio then asks: \"I'm having trouble understanding... why exactly do you need my help?\"",
      "Choices": [
        "\"We re really scared.\"",
        "Tell Horatio that the ghost won't understand you.",
        "Scratch your head."
      ],
      "LoopBack": true,
      "Responses": [
        "\"Go figure... security guards scared of a ghost that probably isn't real.  Come back when you've grown up, please.  I don't have time for this.\" Horatio sternly replies, belittling you in the process.  He walks away.  Great.  Now you've caused a bug in the text adventure's code... I didn't expect you to choose to do that.  Now Horatio's despawned out of the world and I can't get him back.  Why do you enjoy breaking my games so much?  Do you find pleasure in stressing me and my code out?  I am very disappointed in you, player.  I guess I'll just have to trigger the game over sequence and make you start all over.  I hope you're happy now.",
        "You anxiously reply, with a noticeable stutter, \"W-we tried t-to talk to t-the g-g-ghost... b-but it d-didn't u-understand us! W-w-we were uhhh... uhm... w-wondering i-if you would b-be able t-to h-help u-us s-s-speak to it...\"",
        "You scratch your head.  Horatio's confused, but now your head isn't itchy.  I'm pretty sure some dandruff came out of your hair though.  Do you even shower? Gross!"
      ],
      "CorrectChoice": 1
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 0,
      "Prompt": "Horatio is confused for your health.  \"Are you two okay..? Your skin is beat red, almost flourescent.  That stutter also seems pretty nasty.  I can't tell if you two are seriously that terrified or if there's a medical emergency on our hands. Do I need to call 112?\"\r\n\r\n\"Anyway... I can certainly try.\"",
      "Choices": [
        "Take a few deep breaths.",
        "This might be a medical emergency..."
      ],
      "CorrectChoice": 0,
      "Responses": [
        "You begin performing common breathing exercises to calm yourself down.  In.... out.... in... out... Once you're calm, you reply \"You'll understand when you see who it is... Trust me... Come stand guard with us at the tower and you'll see it.\"",
        "You start to feel dizzy, as if you're about to pass out.  Your coworker screams \"CALL AN AMBULANCE.\"  Horatio dials 112, the Danish number for ambulances and fire.  Somehow, cellphones exist in this time period.  Either way, because I'm a horrible programmer, I cannot circumvent this medical emergency and you subsequently pass away before the cellphone finishes dialong.  Rest in peace."
      ]
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 1,
      "Prompt": "LATER THAT NIGHT...\r\n\r\nYou, your coworker, and Horatio are at the guard tower where the ghost was initially seen.  It's another cold night with no activity going on in the vast darkness. The three of you are bored out of your minds and waiting for the ghost to appear.\r\n\r\nWhat do you do?",
      "Choices": [
        "Drink some hot chocolate.",
        "Break out a deck of cards.",
        "Ask Horatio for some Latin lessons.",
        "Scream \"Hello? Ghost? Are you there? Show yourself!\""
      ],
      "CorrectChoice": 3,
      "Responses": [
        "It's too cold out to reliably brew hot chocolate. Sorry!",
        "The other two of you can't agree on what card game to play and the argument gets too heated and full of bickering.  Your coworker draws his blade and says \"Enough. We need to be focusing on that ghost. Stop arguing about those stupid cards or I'm stabbing both of you.\" Horatio is dumbfounded, you silently panic, and the three of you hesitantly get back to guarding.",
        "Horatio, not in the mood to give Latin lessons, grins and says \"Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet.  That's Latin for: leave me alone, please.\"  Little do you know, that's actually dummy text because I'm too busy remembering how to code and do not have time to learn Latin. I can't even remember if those are even Latin words I just typed.",
        "You stand tall, facing into the cold emptiness of the dark night, and let out a loud yell heard clearly from miles away. \"SHOW YOURSELF TO US, GHOST!\"  I'm fairly certain you disturbed the peaceful resting of a few people in that graveyard over there...  Conveniently, you're waiting for just that."
      ],
      "LoopBack": true
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 1,
      "Prompt": "Your echoing scream was so loud and far-reaching that it woke up the ghost of Hamlet's late father.  He looks ETERNALLY ANGRY, looks you dead in the eye, and then looks at Horatio, and says something in Latin.  Horatio translates and says \"The ghost said: Why did you wake me up from my sleep? I was comfortable. What in God's name do you want?\"",
      "Choices": [
        "\"Can I walk through you?\"",
        "\"What did YOU want last night?\"",
        "\"Take me with you! Please! I can't stand this world of text anymore! This is not a good way to live a life!\""
      ],
      "CorrectChoice": 1,
      "LoopBack": true,
      "Responses": [
        "The ghost is just annoyed and insulted now. \"Hello? I'M A GHOST. You tried to stab me earlier with that blade and IT went through me. What did you expect?\"",
        "The ghost remembers the encounter from last night.  \"Oh... I was going to tell you I had a message for my son, Lord Hamlet. I was going to ask where he was, but neither of you idiots could understand me because you were too busy avoiding an urgent trip to the water closet.\"",
        "The ghost confidently says \"As you wish!\" as he tries to interact beyond the grave with this game's debugger to shut it down.  Unfortunately, because this program isn't that advanced, there's no way for him to do so. He tried to trigger a \"Game Over\" screen to give you the choice to exit or restart, but he failed to realize that I scripted this specific scene to not end the game when you pick a bad option.  I guess your wish is actually MY command, and I just defied you. How does it feel?"
      ]
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 1,
      "Prompt": "Horatio explains to the ghost that not everyone in the world speaks Latin. \"If you were half as intelligent as I am, you would know this,\" he says.  The ghost shrugs.  \"Hmph. Well, I have a messahe for my son.\" the ghost replies. \"Are you two capable of delivering it?\" he asks, concerned.",
      "Choices": [
        "Lie, and say Hamlet died.",
        "\"You're not real.\"",
        "\"Ugh. Fine.\""
      ],
      "LoopBack": true,
      "CorrectChoice": 2,
      "Responses": [
        "You decide to confidently say \"But Lord Hamlet died yesterday of a heart attack!\" The ghost looks shocked and worried for a second, but quickly realizes you lied. \"How could that be? I'm a ghost! If Hamlet were dead, would he not be a ghost too? Liar!\"",
        "The ghost replies, in a smug yet oddly philosophical voice, \"How can you prove that? After all, you can see me. You can hear me. You've certainly tried to touch me. In fact, I just farted and I know you can smell it. Can you really prove that I'm not real? Are you real? Is this tower real? What is life? What is the universe? What does this all mean?\"\r\n\r\nHoratio says \"42.\"\r\n\r\nThe ghost cuts him off. \"Shut up. I'm trying to prove a point. Now, will ANY of you deliver my message to Hamlet?\"",
        "\"Good,\" the ghost replies."
      ]
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 1,
      "Prompt": "The ghost starts to explain the true story about his death.  Something to do with adultory or something.  I can't remember, read the actual Hamlet play!  I didn't expect anyone to actually play this far into this text adventure.  I'm starting to run out of ideas.  Either way, eventually the ghost shuts his mouth and disappears.  What will you do with the information he's given you?",
      "Choices": [
        "Ask Horatio to pass the message on for you.",
        "Report the incident to the king and leave Hamlet out of it, possibly avoiding an entire extra 4 acts of hell.",
        "File a bug report for my code because you're not satisfied with my spin on Hamlet."
      ],
      "CorrectChoice": 1,
      "LoopBack": true,
      "Responses": [
        "In the midst of another anxiety attack, on the verge of wetting yourself, you ask Horatio if he'll deal with this for you. \"No. I've dealt with enough of this already. Grow up.\" he says in a stern voice.",
        "You go to leave the tower to report the ghost incident to the king, leaving Hamlet out of it. However, William Shakespeare himself magically appears in the doorway, blocking you.\r\n\r\n\"I knoweth what thou art trying to doth, but t is not what i've did plan.  Bethink of something else.  I wanteth not thee tamp'ring with mine own st'ry liketh yond.\"\r\n\r\nDon't ask me what that means.  However, what William didn't realize, is that *I* control this game.  *I am the programmer!*  You lost the ability to control this story centuries ago, my sweet Billy. I think it'd be entertaining to see what the player decides to do to you.",
        "I'm sorry you aren't satisfied with this game, but you should have read the BIG DISCLAIMER at the start saying what this really is.  I'm not accepting bug reports.  Replaying scene..."
      ]
    },
    {
      "Act": 0,
      "Scene": 1,
      "Prompt": "As the developer, I give you - the player - the ability to defy Shakespeare's wishes.  I want you to tell the King what the ghost told you.  Let's avoid 80% of the story of Hamlet.  Let's do this.  What's your plan?",
      "Choices": [
        "Climb through the tower's window, and carefully climb the side of the tower until you reach the ground.  Completely circumvent Shakespeare in the process.",
        "Stab Shakespeare with your sword and go through the door.",
        "Ask Shakespare nicely to step aside."
      ],
      "LoopBack": true,
      "CorrectChoice": 1,
      "Responses": [
        "The window is locked shut.  Smashing through it is effortless, as somehow bullet-proof and smash-proof glass exists in this time.",
        "You pull out your blade, and go for a fatal blow. At first, Shakespeare blocks the attack. Then, epic battle music plays. Horatio and your coworker both quietly retreat as a furious battle between you and William Shakespeare himself takes place.  The two of you sword-fight all the way down the tower to ground level.  Little do the two of you know, Horatio and the coworker have already made it to the king and reported the ghost incident.  Realizing this could be happening, you taunt Shakespeare.\r\n\r\n\"You know, you have no clue what my friends are doing right now! While I'm drawing out your last moments, your pitiful story is being dismantled! You're nothing but a waste of text on a screen!\"\r\n\r\nShakespeare lets his guard down trying to come up with a rebuttle.\r\n\r\nYou deliver the fatal blow.  william Shakespeare has fallen.\r\n\r\nI've just spilled coffee all over my keyboard.  You've done it.  Take a deep breath.  It's all over.  You've made it through.  You've saved many future generations of children the hassle of \"conquering\" Shakespeare and Hamlet.\r\n\r\nYour life has been fulfilled, and my work as a developer is done.",
        "Shakespeare says \"No.\""
      ]
    }
  ]
}
